A Guide to the George Green Shackelford Student Papers, 1963-1989
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
George Green Shackelford Student Papers, 1963-1989.
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2011-006
2.0 cu. ft. 5 boxes
The collection contains student papers from Dr. George Green Shackelford's Historic Preservation classes spanning 1963-1989.
Shackelford, George Green
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The George Green Shackelford Student Papers were donated to Special Collections in 2011.
Biographical Note
Geroge G. Shackelford (1921-2010) was a Professor of History at Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University from 1955-1986, and Professor Emeritus since 1986. Among various projects, Shackelford helped start the renovations of Smithfield Plantation at Virginia Tech. He also served on the Board of Advisors of the National Trust for Historic Preservation and on the board of the Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiquities.
Shackelford was married to Grace Howard McConnell Shackelford. He died in November 2010.
Scope and Content
The collection contains student papers from Dr. George Green Shackelford's Historical Preservation classes spanning 1963-1989. The paper topics cover specific people, places, or general geographic locations throughout Virginia, as well as some locations in West Virginia and North Carolina. Papers detail the history and design of the building or structure in question, and often include pictures and floor plans. Items have been kept in their original order as organized by Dr. Shackelford.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in alphabetical order, as organized by Dr. Shackelford.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
George Green Shackelford Papers, c.1955-1986. Ms83-008. The collection contains clippings, correspondence, memoranda, bulletins, scrapbooks, and other materials relating to the APVA; the National Trust; the New River Historical Association; the Virginia Landmark Commission the Democratic Committee of Montgomery County (Virginia); the Visiting Scholar Committee of the College of Arts and Sciences for VPI Blacksburg, Virginia, and Southwest Virginia history; historic properties in Blacksburg and Southwest Virginia, particularly Smithfield Plantation; and of Virginia and VPI&SU related topics. Please note: This collection is open for research, but it is unprocessed.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University--Dept. of History.
Local Subjects:
Local/Regional History
Contents List
- 1127 Second Street, Roanoke, 1982. (Box-folder 1-1)
- A Style Sheet for Term Papers, 1967. (Box-folder 1-2)
- Albemarle Churches, 1981. (Box-folder 1-3)
- Allegheny Springs, 1984. (Box-folder 1-4)
- Allegheny Turnpike, 1969. (Box-folder 1-5)
- Allen Caperton, 1986. (Box-folder 1-6)
- Architecture of Colonial and Revolutionary Virginia, 1975. (Box-folder 1-7)
- Bedford County Houses, 1983. (Box-folder 1-8)
- Beechwood Plantation, 1986. (Box-folder 1-9)
- Botetourt County Jail, 1980. (Box-folder 1-10)
- Botetourt Structures, 1980-1986. (Box-folder 1-11)
- Catawba Red Sulphur Springs, 1977. (Box-folder 1-12)
- Chesterfield County Courthouse, 1977. (Box-folder 1-13)
- Clarke County, VA, 1989. (Box-folder 1-14)
- Craig County Courthouse and Jail, 1977-1983. (Box-folder 1-15)
- Cumberland County Courthouse, 1977. (Box-folder 1-16)
- Danville Structures, 1977-1981. (Box-folder 1-17)
- Egyptian Style Architecture in U.S., 1967. (Box-folder 1-18)
- Fairfax County, 1980. (Box-folder 1-19)
- Fauquier White Sulphur Springs, 1977-1980. (Box-folder 1-20)
- Fieldale, VA, 1988. (Box-folder 1-21)
- Floyd Structures, 1976-1981. (Box-folder 2-1)
- Fluvanna County, 1984. (Box-folder 2-2)
- Fort Chiswell, 1976. (Box-folder 2-3)
- Franklin County Jail, 1980-1986. (Box-folder 2-4)
- Fredericksburg, 1963-1987. (Box-folder 2-5)
- Fredericksburg Courthouse, 1979-1985. (Box-folder 2-6)
- George Hancock, 1966-1974. (Box-folder 2-7)
- Germanic Houses and Music, 1984. (Box-folder 2-8)
- Giles County Structures, 1977-1987. (Box-folder 2-9)
- Gordonsville, VA, 1971-1981. (Box-folder 2-10)
- Greenbriar, n.d. (Box-folder 2-11)
- Hanover County Courthouse, 1979-1988. (Box-folder 2-12)
- Hanover County Houses, 1980. (Box-folder 2-13)
- Hardy County, WV, 1987. (Box-folder 2-14)
- Henry County Courthouse, 1977-1989. (Box-folder 2-15)
- Hoge and Plank Farm, 1980. (Box-folder 2-16)
- J. Hoge Tyler and Bellehampton, n.d. (Box-folder 2-17)
- Jefferson County Courthouse, 1978. (Box-folder 2-18)
- Lancaster, VA Houses, 1984. (Box-folder 2-19)
- Land Policies, 1971. (Box-folder 2-20)
- Lead Mines of Wythe County, 1975. (Box-folder 2-21)
- Log Cabins, 1985-1989. (Box-folder 3-1)
- Loudon County, 1987. (Box-folder 3-2)
- Lynchburg's Urban Slaves, 1963-1970. (Box-folder 3-3)
- Marion, VA Structures, 1984. (Box-folder 3-4)
- Mecklenburg County, n.d. (Box-folder 3-5)
- Montgomery County Waifs and Wards, 1977. (Box-folder 3-6)
- Mufreesboro, NC Houses, 1980. (Box-folder 3-7)
- New River Navigation, 1982-1983. (Box-folder 3-8)
- Newport, VA Church, 1980. (Box-folder 3-9)
- Orkney Springs, 1977. (Box-folder 3-10)
- Patrick County Jail, 1980-1985. (Box-folder 3-11)
- Petersburg Taverns, n.d. (Box-folder 3-12)
- Pittsylvania County Courthouse, n.d. (Box-folder 3-13)
- Portsmouth, VA, 1980. (Box-folder 3-14)
- Pulaski County, 1980-1981. (Box-folder 3-15)
- Pulaski County, 1985. (Box-folder 3-16)
- Pulaski County, 1985-1986. (Box-folder 3-17)
- Pulaski County Churches, 1981-1982. (Box-folder 4-1)
- Pulaski Courthouse, 1988-1990. (Box-folder 4-2)
- Pulaski Jail and Cemetery, 1980. (Box-folder 4-3)
- Pulaski Top Ten, 1985. (Box-folder 4-4)
- Radford City, 1980-1984. (Box-folder 4-5)
- Richmond Churches and Houses, 1967-1980. (Box-folder 4-6)
- Roanoke City Structures, 1980-1989. (Box-folder 4-7)
- Roanoke County Courthouse, 1977. (Box-folder 4-8)
- Rockbridge County, 1980-1988. (Box-folder 4-9)
- Salem and Roanoke County Structures, 1981-1985. (Box-folder 4-10)
- Sears and Roebuck House in Alexandria, VA, 1989. (Box-folder 4-11)
- Shutters and Windows 1750-1820, n.d. (Box-folder 4-12)
- Smith County Courthouse (Marion), 1980. (Box-folder 4-13)
- Smithfield Restoration, n.d. (Box-folder 5-1)
- Spotsylvania County Massaponax Baptist Church, 1981. (Box-folder 5-2)
- Springs of Virginia, 1976-1980. (Box-folder 5-3)
- Staunton, Augusta County Houses, Roads, and Churches, 1981. (Box-folder 5-4)
- Swann, 1969. (Box-folder 5-5)
- Tayloe of Roanoke County, 1980. (Box-folder 5-6)
- Tayloe and Cloverdale Furnace, 1983. (Box-folder 5-7)
- Tayloe Slaves at Mt. Airy, 1984. (Box-folder 5-8)
- Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1979-1987. (Box-folder 5-9)
- Wade and Wiley House, 1980. (Box-folder 5-10)
- Warm Springs, 1976. (Box-folder 5-11)
- William Christian, 1975. (Box-folder 5-12)
- Warren County, NC, n.d. (Box-folder 5-13)
- Warrenton, VA, n.d. (Box-folder 5-14)
- Washington County Structures, 1980-1981. (Box-folder 5-15)
- Westover, 1976. (Box-folder 5-16)
- Windows, 1976. (Box-folder 5-17)
- Woodlawn Plantation, 1983. (Box-folder 5-18)
- Wythe County Jail and Courthouse, 1977-1980. (Box-folder 5-19)
- Wythe County Houses, 1979-1982. (Box-folder 5-20)
- Wytheville and Wythe County Structures, 1976-1989. (Box-folder 5-21)